<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-11T01:40:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Welcome to my life!</title><subtitle>This is a website based on my personal life, my accomplishments, travels etc. I hope you have fun while reading about my life!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My trip to Berlin so far</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/07/03/trip.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My trip to Berlin so far" /><published>2023-07-03T23:24:30+02:00</published><updated>2023-07-03T23:24:30+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/07/03/trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/07/03/trip.html"><![CDATA[<p style="float: left; width:400px">
One of the best perks of being a student is the opportunity to participate in Work&amp;Travel.
The agencies in our country that give this offer have trips to Germany and the USA. This year I decided 
that I want to visit Germany. I chose Berlin, because first of all it's the capital of Germany and also I wanted
my visit to be always exciting. My two friends and I arrived on the 1st of July and so far we have visited all of Berlin's best landmarks.
First we started off with the Berlin Wall. It was quite exciting to think that only a wall has left that much 
history in a city.
<br /> <br />
Then, we visited the "Fernsehturm" which is one of the tallest building in Berlin. It was really fun watching
it from below, as it looked like the building was moving.
</p>
<p><img src="/assets/images/wall.jpg" alt="" style="height:400px; width:300px; display: inline-block" /></p>
<p style="float: right; width: 400px; clear:both">
Next on the map was the "Brandenburg Tor". The Brandenburg Tor stands tall and majestic, 
an iconic symbol of Berlin. Its neoclassical design features grand columns, a central archway, and a striking chariot perched on top. The sandstone facade is adorned with intricate details, while the impressive Quadriga statue commands attention. The Tor's presence exudes a sense of history and significance, 
inviting visitors to marvel at its timeless beauty.
<br /><br />
We also wanted to visit the Zoo, so the easiest way to get there was by walking. It was on of the longest
but most peaceful walks I've had in a long time. In the park we saw the Siegessäule, which is placed in the center of
a roundabout. 
</p>
<p><img src="/assets/images/turm.jpg" alt="" style="height:400px; width:300px; display: inline-block" />
<img src="/assets/images/barnden.jpg" alt="" style="height:400px; width:300px; display: inline-block; margin-top: 10px" />
<img src="/assets/images/zoo.jpg" alt="" style="height:400px; width:300px; display: inline-block; margin-top: 10px" /></p>
<p style="display: inline-block; width: 200px; position: relative; left:325px; bottom: 650px">
    I can assure you that this was the most interesting day I've had so far here and I hope there will be more!
</p>

<hr />]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Veb-stranica" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the best perks of being a student is the opportunity to participate in Work&amp;Travel. The agencies in our country that give this offer have trips to Germany and the USA. This year I decided that I want to visit Germany. I chose Berlin, because first of all it's the capital of Germany and also I wanted my visit to be always exciting. My two friends and I arrived on the 1st of July and so far we have visited all of Berlin's best landmarks. First we started off with the Berlin Wall. It was quite exciting to think that only a wall has left that much history in a city. Then, we visited the "Fernsehturm" which is one of the tallest building in Berlin. It was really fun watching it from below, as it looked like the building was moving. Next on the map was the "Brandenburg Tor". The Brandenburg Tor stands tall and majestic, an iconic symbol of Berlin. Its neoclassical design features grand columns, a central archway, and a striking chariot perched on top. The sandstone facade is adorned with intricate details, while the impressive Quadriga statue commands attention. The Tor's presence exudes a sense of history and significance, inviting visitors to marvel at its timeless beauty. We also wanted to visit the Zoo, so the easiest way to get there was by walking. It was on of the longest but most peaceful walks I've had in a long time. In the park we saw the Siegessäule, which is placed in the center of a roundabout. I can assure you that this was the most interesting day I've had so far here and I hope there will be more!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Places I would like to visit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/26/places.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Places I would like to visit" /><published>2023-06-26T19:43:20+02:00</published><updated>2023-06-26T19:43:20+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/26/places</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/26/places.html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are some of the places from all around the world that I would love to visit if I had the chance.</p>
<ol style="text-align: justify">
<li>
<b>New York City</b>
<ul style="list-style: none">
<li>
I have always been captivated by the vibrant energy and cultural diversity of New York City, and visiting this iconic metropolis is a dream of mine. 
From the towering skyscrapers of Manhattan to the artistic spirit of Brooklyn, there is an undeniable allure that pulls me towards this urban wonderland.
I am particularly excited about exploring the bustling streets of Times Square, strolling through Central Park's serene beauty, 
and indulging in the city's world-class cuisine. 
The thought of immersing myself in the pulsating rhythm of the city, witnessing Broadway shows, and discovering hidden gems in the various neighborhoods fills 
me with anticipation.
<img src="/assets/images/newyork.jpg" alt="" style="height: 382px; width: 680px" />
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<b>Paris</b>
<ul style="list-style: none">
<li>
The reason I want to visit Paris is because of how wonderful it looks. The thought of strolling along the romantic banks of the Seine, gazing at the magnificent architecture of the Eiffel Tower,
and getting lost in the artistic masterpieces at the Louvre Museum fills me with a sense of wonder.
I can see myself sitting in a café, drinking coffee and eating croissant, while wondering what my next landmark to visit would be. Sounds really <i>magnifique</i>!
<img src="/assets/images/paris.jpg" alt="" style="height: 382px; width: 680px" />
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<b>Berlin</b>
<ul style="list-style: none">
<li>
My passion for Berlin is uncontainable. The city's vibrant atmosphere, rich history, and creative spirit have ignited a fire within me.
From exploring its iconic landmarks to immersing myself in the diverse communities,
Berlin constantly inspires and fuels my enthusiasm. The city's ability to reinvent itself while 
honoring its past is a testament to its progressive mindset and limitless possibilities. 
Berlin is not just a place- it's a source of endless inspiration that fuels my passion.
<img src="/assets/images/berlin.jpg" alt="" style="height: 382px; width: 680px" />
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<b>Ibiza</b>
<ul style="list-style: none">
<li>
My wish to visit Ibiza burns brightly within me, 
as this enchanting island beckons me with its irresistible allure. 
I yearn to immerse myself in the pulsating energy and vibrant nightlife that has made Ibiza a world-renowned destination.
The thought of dancing to the rhythm of world-class DJs, surrounded by the captivating 
Mediterranean landscape, fills me with anticipation. I crave the sun-kissed beaches,
the crystal-clear turquoise waters, and the blissful moments of relaxation under the warm Mediterranean sun.
Ibiza's unique blend of natural beauty, stunning architecture, and a bohemian atmosphere 
holds the promise of an unforgettable adventure. I dream of exploring its charming old town, 
discovering hidden coves, 
and experiencing the exhilarating atmosphere of the legendary Ibiza parties. 
<img src="/assets/images/ibiza.jpg" alt="" style="height: 382px; width: 680px" />
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Veb-stranica" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are some of the places from all around the world that I would love to visit if I had the chance. New York City I have always been captivated by the vibrant energy and cultural diversity of New York City, and visiting this iconic metropolis is a dream of mine. From the towering skyscrapers of Manhattan to the artistic spirit of Brooklyn, there is an undeniable allure that pulls me towards this urban wonderland. I am particularly excited about exploring the bustling streets of Times Square, strolling through Central Park's serene beauty, and indulging in the city's world-class cuisine. The thought of immersing myself in the pulsating rhythm of the city, witnessing Broadway shows, and discovering hidden gems in the various neighborhoods fills me with anticipation. Paris The reason I want to visit Paris is because of how wonderful it looks. The thought of strolling along the romantic banks of the Seine, gazing at the magnificent architecture of the Eiffel Tower, and getting lost in the artistic masterpieces at the Louvre Museum fills me with a sense of wonder. I can see myself sitting in a café, drinking coffee and eating croissant, while wondering what my next landmark to visit would be. Sounds really magnifique! Berlin My passion for Berlin is uncontainable. The city's vibrant atmosphere, rich history, and creative spirit have ignited a fire within me. From exploring its iconic landmarks to immersing myself in the diverse communities, Berlin constantly inspires and fuels my enthusiasm. The city's ability to reinvent itself while honoring its past is a testament to its progressive mindset and limitless possibilities. Berlin is not just a place- it's a source of endless inspiration that fuels my passion. Ibiza My wish to visit Ibiza burns brightly within me, as this enchanting island beckons me with its irresistible allure. I yearn to immerse myself in the pulsating energy and vibrant nightlife that has made Ibiza a world-renowned destination. The thought of dancing to the rhythm of world-class DJs, surrounded by the captivating Mediterranean landscape, fills me with anticipation. I crave the sun-kissed beaches, the crystal-clear turquoise waters, and the blissful moments of relaxation under the warm Mediterranean sun. Ibiza's unique blend of natural beauty, stunning architecture, and a bohemian atmosphere holds the promise of an unforgettable adventure. I dream of exploring its charming old town, discovering hidden coves, and experiencing the exhilarating atmosphere of the legendary Ibiza parties.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fun Facts About Me!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/25/fun-facts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fun Facts About Me!" /><published>2023-06-25T17:12:55+02:00</published><updated>2023-06-25T17:12:55+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/25/fun-facts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/25/fun-facts.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, for starters I believe that I’m a really outgoing and caring person, I love spending time with my friends and family
and I’m a big animal-lover. Enough chit-chatting, let me start with some fun-facts that would describe who I am.
<br /></p>
<ol>
<li>
<b>I hate waking up early!</b>
<ul>
<li style="list-style: none">
For me, waking up early is one of the hardest thing to do. I enjoy sleeping, so when I have to wake up early for classes I have to mentally prepare
myself to be able to be concentrated and listen the lecture :D . Also, I study way better at night and actually enjoy finishing my studies after midnight, then sleep at least 9 hours to feel
refreshed the next day.
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<b>I am a vegetarian.</b>
<ul>
<li style="list-style: none">
Yes, many people are surprised when I tell them this and I sometimes find it funny when they have questions like: "How do you live without meat?!", or "How do you consume protein?", but I 
don't mind giving them answers. I got used to the absence of meat in my diet, and I've never craved it. That is one of the main reasons why I stopped eating it. 
But I have to admit, sometimes being a vegetarian is difficult when going to restaurants, where there aren't many vegetarian options, but I always find a way to manage in those type of situations.
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<b>I have a black cat.</b>
<ul>
<li style="list-style: none">
Many people think that black cats are bad luck, but I strongly disagree. My cat is named Mambo, and he is the sweetest thing in my life.
He's a rescue, as my family and I rescued him from being tossed in a garbage container and pasted with glue all over his fur. He was only 2 months old when we rescued him
and this year he'll be turning 6! It's crazy how the time flies! 
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<b>I used to play the violin.</b>
<ul>
<li style="list-style: none">
When I was in elementary school, I also used to go to a musical school, specifically "DMBUC Ilija Nikolovski-Luj" in Skopje, where 
I learned how to play the violin. But unfortunately, after finishing elementary and going to high school I stopped playing it regularly, as I didn't have much time to study
and spend time playing it.
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<b>I always knew that my profession with be something linked with computer science.</b>
<ul>
<li style="list-style: none">
Ever since I was little, I've loved spending time in front of the computer, regardless of whether it was for educational or entertainment purposes. So, that's when I decided that
I wanted to spend my life learning about programming and software engineering. I currently study software engineering at FINKI but I also have interest in data science, so I can't wait to get to the 6th semester,
because that's when I'll have a subject about it.
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Veb-stranica" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, for starters I believe that I’m a really outgoing and caring person, I love spending time with my friends and family and I’m a big animal-lover. Enough chit-chatting, let me start with some fun-facts that would describe who I am. I hate waking up early! For me, waking up early is one of the hardest thing to do. I enjoy sleeping, so when I have to wake up early for classes I have to mentally prepare myself to be able to be concentrated and listen the lecture :D . Also, I study way better at night and actually enjoy finishing my studies after midnight, then sleep at least 9 hours to feel refreshed the next day. I am a vegetarian. Yes, many people are surprised when I tell them this and I sometimes find it funny when they have questions like: "How do you live without meat?!", or "How do you consume protein?", but I don't mind giving them answers. I got used to the absence of meat in my diet, and I've never craved it. That is one of the main reasons why I stopped eating it. But I have to admit, sometimes being a vegetarian is difficult when going to restaurants, where there aren't many vegetarian options, but I always find a way to manage in those type of situations. I have a black cat. Many people think that black cats are bad luck, but I strongly disagree. My cat is named Mambo, and he is the sweetest thing in my life. He's a rescue, as my family and I rescued him from being tossed in a garbage container and pasted with glue all over his fur. He was only 2 months old when we rescued him and this year he'll be turning 6! It's crazy how the time flies! I used to play the violin. When I was in elementary school, I also used to go to a musical school, specifically "DMBUC Ilija Nikolovski-Luj" in Skopje, where I learned how to play the violin. But unfortunately, after finishing elementary and going to high school I stopped playing it regularly, as I didn't have much time to study and spend time playing it. I always knew that my profession with be something linked with computer science. Ever since I was little, I've loved spending time in front of the computer, regardless of whether it was for educational or entertainment purposes. So, that's when I decided that I wanted to spend my life learning about programming and software engineering. I currently study software engineering at FINKI but I also have interest in data science, so I can't wait to get to the 6th semester, because that's when I'll have a subject about it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">About me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/25/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About me" /><published>2023-06-25T16:48:55+02:00</published><updated>2023-06-25T16:48:55+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/25/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/veb-stranica/jekyll/update/2023/06/25/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify">Hi everyone, my name is Jovana Siljanovska and I'm 19 years old. I am currently a student at FINKI, and have just 
finished my first year there. I went to "Orce Nikolov" high school and have lived in Skopje my entire life. My favorite color is 
purple and love music. On this blog, you will get to know me better, even if we haven't even met in person.
</p>
<p><img src="/assets/images/orce.jpg" alt="" style="height:400px; width:800px; display: inline-block" />
This was my high school - Orce Nikolov
<br />
<img src="/assets/images/finki.jpg" alt="" style="height:400px; width:800px; display: inline-block" />
And this is FINKI!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Veb-stranica" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi everyone, my name is Jovana Siljanovska and I'm 19 years old. I am currently a student at FINKI, and have just finished my first year there. I went to "Orce Nikolov" high school and have lived in Skopje my entire life. My favorite color is purple and love music. On this blog, you will get to know me better, even if we haven't even met in person. This was my high school - Orce Nikolov And this is FINKI!]]></summary></entry></feed>